米琼恩
我们得走了
We got to go.
他以前常常坐在屋顶上
He used to sit on the roof.
我们得走了
We have to go.
米琼恩
Michonne!
Michonne.
米琼恩
Michonne!
欢迎来到亚历山大安全区
迷途者的天堂  掠夺者的地狱
你觉得他是什么意思
What do you think he meant?
他希望我们停止反抗救世军吗
Did he want us ‭to stop fighting the Saviors?
向尼根投降吗
Just... surrender to Negan?
我们可以靠边停车
We could pull over.
看看他写了什么
We could read what he wrote.
不  现在还不行  我不能看
No. Not yet. Not me.
瑞克
Rick.
他  卡尔
He -- Carl... He...
给尼根写了封信
wrote a letter to Negan.
我得和简迪斯谈谈
I need to talk to Jadis.
什么
What?
他们有武器  人手
They have weapons... people.
我们不能就此放弃
We can't just give that up.
为什么是现在
Why now?
他们跟我去了救世堂
They went with me to the Sanctuary.
救世军看到了我们
The Saviors saw us there.
他们也会成为目标
They're gonna be a target, too.
我们仍需要他们
We still need them.
他们是我们的盟友  不是他们的
They're ours, not theirs.
该死
Dammit.
《行尸走肉》
尼根
我们监视了山顶寨  道路什么的
Hilltop is covered. The roads and then some.
他们在外面  所以我们要深入搜索
They are out there somewhere, so let's get balls deep
他们可能躲藏的每个旮沓角落
in every nook and cranny they might hole up in.
角落  裂缝和洞穴  各位
Nooks, crannies, and holes, people.
能藏人的任何鬼地方
All that shit outside the box.
看来我们亚历山大的朋友们
Appears our friends at Alexandria
弄了个逃跑计划
had themselves an escape plan.
瑞克的独眼心肝宝贝耍了我
Rick's little one-eyed pride and joy played me.
该死
Damn.
那孩子  就是为末世而生的
That kid -- ‭That kid is built for this shit.
让我出去了结这一切
Let me go out and close this thing.
阿拉特已经去了
Arat's got it for now.
山顶寨情况如何
How'd the Hilltop go?
按照要求做了
As requested.
干得好
Good job.
再加一句好样的
With an extra attaboy on top
因为我知道你不想那样
given I know you didn't want to play it that way.
有加文的消息吗
You hear anything om Gavin?
还没有  但是快了
Not yet, but it's coming.
加文或许一辈子都郁郁寡欢
Gavin may be perpetually pissed off,
但他向来能把分内工作做好
but he keeps his shit dry and tight.
假如不需要我去追捕瑞克一伙
If I'm not running down Rick and company,
你准备让我去干什么
where do you want me?
捡破烂的那群人
Garbage people.
好啊
Good.
消灭那群叛徒也许会...
Eliminating those who reneged might...
让我们弹药不足
leave us a tad short on ammo,
但还是值得的
but it's worth it.
我需要你听好了  西蒙
I need you to hear me on this, Simon.
那些无耻的叛徒也许两面三刀
Those piss-stained double-crossers may have pulled a triple cross,
但这也不能改变他们是个好资源的事实
but it doesn't change the fact that they are still a resource.
所以你得把那口翻腾上来的老血咽下去
So you're gonna choke back whatever shit ‭is stirring up inside you
去提醒他们  和救世军的协议
and remind them ‭that a deal with the Saviors
是坚不可摧的
is a lock, stock, suck my barrel deal.
发出警告  杀鸡儆猴
Deliver the standard message, take one out,
其他人自然会听话
and the rest will fall in line.
只杀一个就好  西蒙
Just one, Simon.
有什么想说的...
If you've got something to say...
就直说吧
say it.
也许我们应该及时止损
Maybe we should cut our losses here.
这些人永远学不乖
These people can't learn the lesson,
无论我们给他们多少次教训
no matter how many times we teach it.
亚历山大  山顶寨
Alexandria, Hilltop,
神之国  捡破烂的...
Kingdom, these garbage rats --
他们像是不了解情况一样
they're not seeming ‭to understand the situation.
一点都不了解
Not one little bit.
所以也许我们该吸取一下教训
So maybe we learn our lesson,
把残渣清理掉
scrape the plates into the trash.
去更远的地方
Move further out.
找其他的社区...
Find other communities to...
去"拯救"
"save."
我现在是使出了浑身的劲
Oh, I am doing my best
才忍住没笑出来
to hold it together right now.
你想止你的损  一意孤行
You wanna cut your losses, take your own advice.
靠杀光所有人来解决问题...
Killing everybody to solve the problem --
那是简单的方法
that is the easy way,
但不是我们的方法
not our way.
我们的所作所为...
What we do...
拯救众生  是很不容易
saving people, it is hard.
但却他妈的很有效果
But it damn well works.
最近可没有
Not lately.
一旦我解决了瑞克
Once I clip Rick,
一切都会归位  西蒙
everything's aces again, Simon.
怎么了
Yeah?
那他妈是什么
What the hell is that?
从山顶寨送来的
A delivery from the Hilltop.
我给你带了工具来处理它
I brought you something to deal with it.
上好膛了
It's charged.
出去
Out.
我们还有38个人质  别轻举妄动
再打开一点
Little bit more.
是迪恩
That's Dean.
这意味着山顶寨的另外38个人质
That means the other "38" that the Hilltop are holding
都是卫星站的
are from the Satellite Outpost.
都是我的人
Those are my people.
我要杀光那些农夫
I'm gonna kill ‭every last one of those farmers!
你只能做我交代的事
You will do exactly what I asked.
我们不能让他们逍遥法外
We can't let 'em get away with this shit.
你只能做
You will do...
你分内的事
your job!
伊妮德
我们是来找你们帮忙的
We came here to ask for your help.
你们真不该来
Well, ‭you shouldn't have.
拜托  能不能...
Hey. Please. Just...
Please. Just...
能谈谈吗
Let's talk about this.
娜塔尼亚是你的家人
Natania was your family.
你来决定  辛蒂
It's up to you, Cyndie.
全听你的
All of it.
我们应该杀了他们
We should just kill them.
我们会脱身的
We're gonna get out of this.
不是因为那个
‭This is...it's not about that.
是她逼的  我别无选择
She made it so I had to do it.
她逼我杀她的
She made me kill her.
我会再做一次的
I'd do it again.
我没得选
I'd have to.
尽管知道会不好受
Even knowing it would feel this way.
谢谢
Thank you.
带到海滩去
Take them to the beach.
-你要杀我们  -带走
- You're going to kill us? ‭- Take them.
这是你的决定
This is your decision.
你要负责
You own it.
辛蒂
Cyndie.
你杀我们  最好不是
You better have a good reason for killing us
只为了一时解气
other than thinking it'll make you feel better.
因为解不了
Because it won't.
赶紧杀了他们吧
Let's just get it over with.
你为什么要杀我们
Why would you kill us?
为了惩罚我们吗
To punish us?
你还不明白吗
I mean, don't you get it?
杀戮本身就是惩罚
Killing is the punishment.
你处决我们
You execute us,
然后我们的人可能会来找我们
then maybe some of ours will come looking for us.
也许你能干掉他们
And maybe you'll take them out,
但最终  会来更多的人
but eventually, ‭enough of them will come back
并且消灭你们
and they will wipe you out.
你祖母自己害死了自己
Your grandmother got herself killed,
所以别再犯同样的错误了
so don't make the same mistake.
放了我们
Just let us go...
我们会继续抗争  你们也能继续藏身
...and we'll keep fighting them and you can keep hiding.
算了
No.
放他们走
They live.
如果我们赢了  你想得到消息吗
If we win, ‭do you even want to know?
想
Yes.
那就帮我们获胜
Then help us win.
我们没杀你俩  就是帮你们获胜了
We're helping you win by not killing you both.
那是我们对反抗事业的贡献
That's our contribution to the cause.
你已经拿走了我们能给的一切
You've taken everything else we could give.
别再回这里了
Don't come here again.
别再试图杀陌生人了
Stop trying to kill strangers.
我们知道我们得杀谁
We know who we have to kill.
我们知道朋友和敌人之间的区别
We know the difference between friends and enemies.
你们也该知道
You should, too.
别回来了
Don't come back.
你知道去车子的路怎么走吗
You know how to get to the car?
知道
Yeah.
好
Good.
不
No.
亚伦  她们不会帮我们
Aaron, ‭they're not gonna help us.
我想回家
I want to go home.
真的  胜过一切
I do, more than anything.
但我不能走
But I can't leave.
她们还没加入战斗呢
Not until they join the fight.
她们不会加入的
They're not joining.
碧翠丝和凯西之前愿意抗争
Beatrice and Kathy ‭were open to fighting before.
我想我能说服她们  我只是需要时间
I think I can convince them. I just need time.
好  那我们都留下
Okay, then we both stay.
你得回去
You need to get back.
告诉玛姬发生了什么  我在做什么
Tell Maggie what's happening, what I'm doing...
你得告诉她别过来
and you need to tell her not to come.
如果你回去  她们会杀了你的
They'll kill you if you go back there.
我不会回去的
I won't go back there.
会没事的
It'll be okay.
不管发生了什么  我都会没事的
No matter what happens, I'll be okay.
跟我保证我们会再见面
Promise me I'll see you again.
保证
Promise.
跟我保证你会没事
Promise me you'll be okay.
去吧
Go.
西蒙
那么
So...
我们要攻击山顶寨吗
we lighting up the Hilltop?
我们要继续按兵不动
Gonna sit on our dicks a mite more.
唉  我们要去垃圾场
Alas, we're going to the landfill.
别担心  加里
No worries, Gary.
丝毫不用担心
Not a single one in the world.
美女
Nellie!
大家不要激动
Everybody keep their horses inside the gate!
毕竟我们是朋友
After all, we're friends.
对吗
Right?
既然说清了这点
Now that that's out of the way,
我们说正事吧
let's get down to the brass tacks.
底线是  我需要道歉
Bottom line, ‭I'm gonna need an apology.
真诚的道歉
The genuine article.
我知道你跟瑞克有私下交易
Now, I know you had ‭your little side deal with Rick.
你们几乎是手拉手来到了我们家
You came to our home, pretty much arm in arm.
尽管我们事先已有过约定
This despite the pre-existing arrangement with us.
你知道我们看到你了  因为我们想杀了你
Now you know we saw you, because we tried to kill you.
所以你有足够的时间准备些什么
So you've had plenty of time to prepare something.
希望是一段感人肺腑的忏悔
A heartfelt act of confession, I hope.
你可以随意参考事先准备好的笔记
Feel free to refer to any notes you may have prepared.
和瑞克没交易
No deal with Rick.
送他过去
Delivered him.
交给你们
Brought to you.
但你们开枪了
But you shot.
胡扯
Bull-shit!
但是不用担心
But no need to worry.
因为你们走运了
'Cause you caught yourself a break --
要我说的话  走大运了
a big ol' break, if you ask me.
只要你们重新履行我们说好的协议
Negan is graciously willing to forgo any punishment,
尼根就会仁慈地免除一切惩罚
provided you agree to revert to the agreed-upon terms of our deal.
只要这样做
You do that...
一切一笔勾销
all is forgiven.
走了狗屎运  对吧
That's some crazy good luck, right?
不过我们得收缴你们的枪支弹药
However, we will be taking all your guns and ammunition.
协议中没这条
Not our deal.
没错
No, it isn't.
但我们现在有这个需求
But we currently have a need.
作为盟友  这种善意的举动
And as friends, you will grant us
将被视作忠心的证明
this neighborly gesture as a sign of good faith.
到处都有危险
Dangers everywhere.
我们也需要枪
Need guns, too.
你们有我们了
Not when you got us.
如果真到了你们需要用枪的时候
And if and when the time comes for you to have guns,
救世军自会提供给你们
the Saviors will provide them for you.
闪闪发光  枪况良好
Spit-shined, ready to go.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是你画的吗
Is this you?
不赖嘛
It's not bad.
之前学的还是后来学的
You learn before or after?
不是学的
Don't learn.
这
This?
与生俱来
Come to know.
为什么要选垃圾场
Why the dump?
有很多好地方可以安家
I mean, there had to be a better place to call home.
我们的地方
Our place.
我们的
Ours.
后面的停机坪是怎么回事
What's the deal with the helipad in back?
那些太阳能板
The solar panels?
这里之前是什么地方
What was this place?
垃圾场
A dump.
我想知道你知不知道
I want to know if you know.
枪给你了
You have guns.
达成协议了吗
We have deal?
我突然发现我还没有得到正式的道歉
It occurs to me that I've not yet received the full definition of an apology.
我觉得你们似乎承认了背叛
I feel like I've gotten some transgressional acknowledgment,
这些枪自然算补偿
the guns certainly cover restitution.
但我还没感觉到
But what I'm not yet feeling...
悔恨
is the remorse.
有悔恨
There is remorse.
不
No!
再说一遍
Say it again!
有悔恨  你个混蛋
There is remorse, you son of a bitch!
不  不  不
No, no, no.
我觉得你不是真心的
I don't think you mean that.
开枪吧  兄弟们
Light it up, gents.
立刻开枪
Light it up now!
任务完成了吗
Got it done?
远不止此
That and then some.
你没事吧
You good?
加文没消息
Nothing on Gavin.
想让我回头
Want me to turn back around,
再出去一趟查清楚吗
roll out, end the mystery?
我已经派一队人去了
I already sent a team out there.
我想他一定没事
Well, I'm sure he's A-okay.
如果真出事了  我们再警告一次
And if not, we'll just send another message.
告诉我具体过程
So, tell me how it went.
标准的上门警告
Standard message and delivery.
通过示范让他们知道了
Showed 'em and told 'em.
有悔恨
There was remorse.
尼根
Negan.
怎么了
Yeah. What is it?
是瑞克
It's Rick.
简迪斯
快来
Come on!
瑞克
Rick.
这里发生了什么
What happened here?
救世军来了
The Saviors.
我们怎么出去
Well, how do we get out?
怎么进来
Get out...
就怎么出去
how you got in.
以前没有垃圾山
These weren't heaps before.
只是垃圾
It was just trash
一片片铺在地上  看不到尽头
laid out, as far as the eye could see.
我以前常来这里找东西  在上面作画
I used to come here to find things to paint on.
金属板
Metal sheets.
布料
Fabrics.
后来  一切改变之后
And then after... everything changed...
我意识到  这个地方就是块画布
I realized this whole place was a canvas.
我们就是颜料
That we were the paint.
我们可以创造新的事物
We could create something new.
我们可以成为新的事物
We could become something new.
我们确实变了
We did.
这里本是我们的世界
This was our world.
与其他人都不同
Apart from everyone else.
从各方面来说都是
In every way.
这是你的错
You did this.
都是因为你
This is because of you.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我们冲出去
We're gonna run for it.
带我一起走
Let me come with you.
远离它们就行
Just until they're gone.
不
Nah.
我受够了她的游戏
I'm done with her games.
反正她也帮不上我们
She can't help us, anyway.
走吧
Come on.
等等  求你了  让我出去
Wait! Please! Just -- Just let me get out!
苹果酱
货架存销*20罐
瑞克
我朝她头顶开枪  我只想赶她走
I shot above her head. I just wanted her gone.
我看到她了  她安全了
Look, I saw her. She made it.
我走之前她跑进了空巷子里
She ran into an empty alley just before I left.
我不想让她死
I didn't want her dead.
我只想让她走
I just wanted her gone.
感觉这就是卡尔所说的事
Feels like ‭what Carl was talking about.
当有选择时  我们该做什么
What we should do when we have a choice.
我需要点时间
I need a se-- I need a second.
没事
It's fine.
爸爸
尼根
尼根  我是卡尔...
我被咬了...
我知道你变成这样是被迫的...
让尼根通话
Get me Negan.
你是谁
Who the hell is asking?
瑞克·格兰姆斯
It's Rick Grimes.
瑞克  瞧你还给我打电话呢
Ricky. Look at you, callin' me up.
不如告诉我你在哪
You wanna tell me where you are
我们当面谈谈吧
so we can do this face-to-face?
卡尔死了
Carl's dead.
他写了很多信
He wrote letters.
其中一封是给你的
He wrote one to you.
他要你停下
He asked you to stop.
他要我停下
He asked me to stop.
他要我们休战
He asked us for peace.
但现在太迟了
But it's too late for that.
即使我们想谈和  也没意义了
Even if we wanted a deal now, it doesn't matter.
我要杀了你
I'm gonna kill you.
发生了什么
How did it happen?
什么
‭What?
他怎么死的
How did he die?
是我们吗
Was it us?
是手榴弹吗
Was it the grenades?
大火吗
The fire?
不是你们
It wasn't you.
卡尔出去帮别人
Carl went out to help someone.
被咬了
And he got bit.
见鬼
God damn it.
妈的  我很遗憾
Shit. I, um...I am sorry.
我想要他加入我
You know, I wanted him to be part of things.
我定了计划
I had plans.
那孩子
He -- That kid --
那孩子是未来
That kid was the future.
只有你死了才有未来
The only future is one where you're dead.
你到底在做什么  瑞克
What the hell are you doing, Rick?
你为什么反抗  你为什么增加难度
Why are you fighting? Why are you making this so hard?
你害死了卡尔
Carl is dead because of you.
因为你非要没事找事
Because you couldn't leave shit well enough alone.
他说不定以后也会因别的而死
I mean, hell, maybe he woulda died some other way.
我们任何人都可能随时蹬腿
Any one of us can get our ticket punched at any second.
但就这情况来说
but in this case --
就这情况来说
in this case...
他是被你害死的
he is dead because of you.
因为你没能在场阻止他做傻事
Because you weren't there to stop him ‭from doing something stupid.
头是你起的  瑞克
You set this course, Rick.
下一个死的是谁
Who's next?
你
You are.
不
No.
但会是某人
But someone is.
你瞧  我阻止了人们死去
You see, I stop people from dying.
我是终极答案
I am the answer.
也许沉痛的教训才能让你意识到
Now, it may have taken a hard lesson for you to hear it,
但你该意识到了
but you should hear it now.
时候到了
It's time.
别再让你的错误决定
Do not let any more of your shit decisions
害死你爱的其他人了
cost you to lose anyone else you love.
那烂摊子
That garbage...
是你的重担
that sticks with you.
直到永远
Forever.
就像卡尔一样
Just like Carl will.
见鬼  我也难受
Hell, I'm feeling it.
我会难受很久的
And I'm gonna be feeling it for a while.
你本可以让我拯救你们所有人
You could have just let me save all of you.
所以我当初才杀了你的朋友们
I mean, that why I killed your friends in the first place.
你可以坐在那里
So, you can sit there
说什么你要杀了我
and you can say ‭that you're gonna kill me,
但你杀不了
but you won't.
你失败了
You failed.
你是个失败的领袖
You failed as a leader,
更重要的是  瑞克  你是个失败的父亲
and most of all, Rick, you failed as a father.
放弃吧
Just give up.
放弃吧  因为你已经输了
Give up, because you have already lost.